{"doc": "Ripper-Reprint.pdf", "url": "http://wheat.agsci.colostate.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/85/2016/02/Ripper-Reprint.pdf", "chunk": "1", "sentences": {"Ripper was released because of its superior grain yield performance under nonirrigated produc-tion in eastern Colorado and superior milling and bread-baking quality.": {"entity 1": {"start": 0, "end": 6, "label": "CVAR"}, "entity 2": {"start": 44, "end": 67, "label": "TRAT"}, "entity 3": {"start": 110, "end": 118, "label": "GPE"}, "entity 4": {"start": 132, "end": 139, "label": "TRAT"}, "entity 5": {"start": 144, "end": 164, "label": "TRAT"}}, "The name Ripper was chosen as a slang term referring to “one that is an excellent example of its kind” (Farlex, 2007).Ripper was selected from the cross CO940606/TAM107R-2 made in 1996 at Fort Collins, CO.": {"entity 1": {"start": 9, "end": 15, "label": "CVAR"}, "entity 2": {"start": 118, "end": 124, "label": "CVAR"}, "entity 3": {"start": 153, "end": 171, "label": "PED"}, "entity 4": {"start": 180, "end": 184, "label": "DATE"}, "entity 5": {"start": 188, "end": 204, "label": "GPE"}}, "CO940606 is an unreleased sib-selection of KS94WGRC29 (PI 586954), a germplasm release from Kansas State University with the pedigree PI 220127/P5//’TAM-200’/KS87H66 (Martin and Harvey, 1997).": {"entity 1": {"start": 0, "end": 8, "label": "CVAR"}, "entity 2": {"start": 43, "end": 53, "label": "CVAR"}, "entity 3": {"start": 55, "end": 64, "label": "ALAS"}, "entity 4": {"start": 92, "end": 115, "label": "ORG"}, "entity 5": {"start": 134, "end": 165, "label": "PED"}}, "TAM107R-2 is an unreleased sib-selection of the hard red winter wheat culti-var Prairie Red (PI 605390; Quick et al.,": {"entity 1": {"start": 0, "end": 9, "label": "CVAR"}, "entity 2": {"start": 48, "end": 52, "label": "TRAT"}, "entity 3": {"start": 53, "end": 56, "label": "TRAT"}, "entity 4": {"start": 57, "end": 63, "label": "TRAT"}, "entity 5": {"start": 64, "end": 69, "label": "CROP"}, "entity 6": {"start": 80, "end": 91, "label": "CVAR"}, "entity 7": {"start": 93, "end": 102, "label": "ALAS"}}, "(Triticum aestivum L.) was tested under experimental line number CO00016 and released by the Colorado Agricultural Experiment Station in August 2006 through an exclusive mar-keting agreement with the Colorado Wheat Research Founda-tion.": {"entity 1": {"start": 65, "end": 72, "label": "ALAS"}, "entity 2": {"start": 93, "end": 133, "label": "ORG"}, "entity 3": {"start": 144, "end": 148, "label": "DATE"}, "entity 4": {"start": 200, "end": 235, "label": "ORG"}}, "Researchers at Colorado State University and USDA-ARS researchers at Manhattan, KS, and St. Paul, MN, participated in the development of Ripper.": {"entity 1": {"start": 15, "end": 40, "label": "ORG"}, "entity 2": {"start": 45, "end": 53, "label": "ORG"}, "entity 3": {"start": 69, "end": 82, "label": "GPE"}, "entity 4": {"start": 88, "end": 100, "label": "GPE"}, "entity 5": {"start": 137, "end": 143, "label": "CVAR"}}}}